adra.ca 2018-01-08

# Privacy & Security – ADRA Canada

## Our Commitment

ADRA Canada is committed to protecting the privacy of its donors, supporters, employees and other stakeholders. We value the trust of those we deal with, and of the public, and recognize that maintaining this trust requires that we be transparent and accountable in how we treat the personal information that you choose to share with us.

During the course of our various activities, we frequently gather and use personal information. We do not collect personally identifying information about you when you visit our site, unless you choose to provide such information to us. Providing such information is strictly voluntary. Anyone from whom we collect such personal information should expect that it will be carefully protected and that any use of or other dealing with this personal information is subject to express or implied consent. Our privacy practices are designed to achieve this.

Depending on where you live, ADRA Canada may not be under any statutory obligations with respect to the protection of the personal information that you provide to us, but ADRA Canada has voluntarily decided to adhere to best practices for the collection, use and disclosure of personal information as outlined in this policy.

## What Personal Information Do We Collect?

Personal information is the information that relates to you as an individual. We will only request information from you that relates directly to the resources or services we are providing to you and we will keep that information active only as long as the uses for which it has been collected are relevant.

Personal information collected by ADRA Canada may include; name, address and other contact information, credit card or bank account information for donation purposes, countries or programs an individual wishes to support, language preference, demographic information such as age and gender, and communication preferences for marketing purposes.

## How Do We Use and Disclose Your Personal Information?

ADRA Canada collects personal information in order to service your account, understand your giving preferences and provide you with relevant communications and marketing materials.

We may share this information with ADRA employees for the purposes of marketing, research and analysis. In certain limited circumstances, it may be necessary to share the information with a third party service provider on a confidential basis. When this occurs, we provide only the information that is required to provide the services and strict terms of confidentiality are established.

## Retention of Personal Information

We will not retain personal information indefinitely. Generally, information is retained for two years after it has become inactive. Files are then destroyed or deleted, except for those on backup drives and financial records which, in accordance with the law, must be retained for seven years. Archived information is not accessible for operational or marketing purposes.

## Privacy Practices

Personal information gathered by our organization is kept in confidence. Our personnel are authorized to access personal information based only on their need to deal with it for the reason(s) for which it was obtained. Safeguards are in place to ensure that personal information is not disclosed or shared more widely than is necessary to achieve the purpose for which it was gathered. We contractually require any person or organization providing services to ADRA Canada to comply with federal and provincial privacy legislation. We also take measures to ensure that the integrity of personal information is maintained and retained only as long as it is required.

We collect, use and disclose personal information only for purposes that a reasonable person would consider appropriate in light of the circumstances. We do not sell, exchange, loan or make available personal information to any other organization. We offer donors and supporters the opportunity to opt not to have their personal information used for purposes beyond those for which it was originally collected.

## Web Site, Electronic Commerce, And Other Safeguards

We keep all personal information confidential and we will have safeguards to protect that information whether it is in print, electronic, or other form. We use password protocols and encryption software to protect personal and other information we receive when a service is requested and/or paid for on-line. Our software is routinely updated to maximize protection of such information. The ADRA Canada Web site uses or may in the future use technology features such as log-in registration, cookies, or click through tracking software. The site also logs information such as Web site IP addresses and browser types. This information is used for analysis purposes and to provide better service for users.

## Access To Personal Information

Subject to certain exceptions, which are provided for by applicable privacy legislation or by the Personal Information Protection and Electronic Documents Act, you have a right to be told what personal information we hold about you. If you wish to verify your information, please contact ADRA Canada’s Privacy Officer as described below. If you find errors or omissions, we will be pleased to make corrections.

## Contact ADRA Canada Regarding Privacy Policies

Questions, concerns or complaints relating to ADRA Canada’s privacy policy on the treatment of personal information can be addressed by writing to:

Attention: Privacy Officer,  
ADRA Canada  
20 Robert St. W.  
Newcastle, Ontario  
L1B 1C6

Further information on privacy and your rights in regard to your personal information may be found on the Web Site of the Privacy Commissioner of Canada at [www.privcom.gc.ca](https://www.priv.gc.ca/en/)

## Mailing Lists and Newsletters:

ADRA Canada offers several opt-in mailing lists for both regular postal mail and electronic mail. Any personally identifiable information provided by you is used for the purpose of delivering the mailing item, renewing your subscription, research and/or marketing. Users may choose to opt-out at anytime by contacting us at 1 (888) 274-ADRA (2372) or by filling out the appropriate form on our website.

## Contacting ADRA Canada Regarding Web Site Operations

If you have any questions about the practices of this site, please contact ADRA Canada

**By Email:**[info@adra.ca](mailto:info@adra.ca)

**By Mail:**  
ADRA Canada  
20 Robert St. W.  
Newcastle, Ontario  
L1B 1C6

**By Phone:**  
General inquiries: 1 (888) 274-ADRA (2372)

## Use of Links

Throughout our Web pages, we provide links to other servers which may contain information of interest to our readers. We take no responsibility for, and exercise no control over, the organizations, views, or accuracy of the information contained on other servers. Creating a text link from your Web site to our site does not require permission.

## Use of Text and Images

If you would like to publish information that you find on our Web site, please send your request to StayInTouch@adra.ca. Where text or images are posted on our site with the permission of the original copyright holder, a copyright statement appears on the page.
